WhatRocks Pro

WhatRocks Pro

===============================================================================================================================================================================================

WhatRocks Pro

WhatRocks Pro

**Privacy policy**

**In English** - [En Français](https://www.whatrocks.co/fr/politique-de-confidentialite)

_As of July 1, 2020_

As the powerhouse of the WhatRocks service as defined below, WhatRocks Inc. (“**WhatRocks**”, “**we**”, or “**us**”) operates on behalf and in the name of WhatRocks Foundation, the non-profit organization that owns and governs the WhatRocks service, to build a global community of registered engaged, purpose-driven individuals, corporations (including but not limited to advertisers, publishers, and event organizers), and charities (each a “**Member**”) that take action together to fund social and environmental change:

1 - Corporations reward Individuals financially with fungible blockchain tokens issued exclusively by WhatRocks and called Rocks™ (“**Digital Tokens**”) when Individuals are exposed to, engage or interact with WhatRocks-enhanced marketing or advertising material such as online banner ads, video or rich media ads, emails, websites and mobile apps (including notifications) as well as any other form of digital or print material.

2 - Individuals use their Digital Tokens to make direct donations to the Charities of their choice or to make giveback purchases of goods and services such as tickets and promo codes to local events and parties (“**Giveback Items**”) from selling Members (“**Sellers**”) who donate the Digital Tokens they have received as payment to the Charities of their own choice.

3 - Charities fund their activities by selling their Digital Tokens for fiat currency to Corporations that need to reward Individuals financially when they are exposed to, engage or interact with their own WhatRocks-enhanced marketing or advertising material.

The mission of WhatRocks is to bring to life the vision of WhatRocks Foundation that individuals everywhere be financially empowered by the marketing and advertising spend of advertisers, so they get money to make donations to the social and environmental causes they care about. To that purpose, WhatRocks has developed a proprietary technology-based ecosystem that includes a technical platform and a suite of tools and products described below to support the development and the management of the WhatRocks community of WhatRocks Foundation, the delivery of WhatRocks-enhanced marketing or advertising material to Members of the WhatRocks Service as well as the processing of transactions such as financial rewards, donations and payments.

As WhatRocks is committed to respecting and protecting your privacy, we have developed this Privacy Policy ("**Privacy Policy**") that applies when anyone uses our Service to help make sure they understand what information WhatRocks collects, what we do with the information we collect, store, process and share and the choices they can make to control their privacy when they use our Service or to correct or change such information (individually and collectively, "**you**", “**they**”). More specifically, when you register to become a Member of the WhatRocks™ community to use the Service, the data and information that you provide or that is generated or inferred directly or indirectly, actively or passively from your use of the Service is collected, stored, processed and used by WhatRocks on behalf and in the name of WhatRocks Foundation. If you do not agree with or you are not comfortable with any aspect of this Privacy Policy, you should immediately discontinue access or use of our Service.

* * *

**Table of Contents**
=====================

* * *

**INTRODUCTION**
----------------

### **Service**

This Privacy Policy applies to WhatRocks.co, WhatRocks™ wallets, websites, applications and platforms, and other WhatRocks™-related sites, applications, communications and services (“**Service**”), including off-site Service, such as our ad services, plugins, cookies, tags, widgets and other software programs, but excluding services that state that they are offered under a different privacy policy.

### **Members and Visitors**

Users of our Service (“**Members**”) including individuals, corporations and charities are required to register to the WhatRocks™ community in order to open their Member account with the associated wallet and to tie all their activities on the Service to this account including but not limited to credits and debits to their wallet, the creation of or participation in fundraisers, the post and view of Giveback Items, and their engagement with personal contacts in the Service to send or respond to invitations to go to a local party or event or participate in a fundraiser. Giveback Items and data on some of our Service is viewable to non-members (“**Visitors**”).

As a registered Member of the WhatRocks™ community, you give your explicit consent to the use of technologies such as cookies and tags to (1) track your browsing journey across websites and applications without limitation to collect all necessary personal data for the purpose of the Service, (2) identify WhatRocks-enhanced marketing or advertising material that you are exposed to, engage or interact with across the web, (3) enable the payment of Rocks™ as a personal data dividend (see below) when you engage with such material, and (4) monetize your personal data including with third-party advertisers and partners pursuant to this Privacy Policy to target you with WhatRocks-enhanced marketing or advertising material in the Service and anywhere on the web and help you earn more Rocks™ as a Dividend when you are exposed to, engage or interact with such material.

As a Visitor or Member, the collection, storage, use and sharing of your personal data is subject to this Privacy Policy (which includes our [Cookie Policy](https://www.whatrocks.co/en/cookie-policy) and other documents referenced in this Privacy Policy) and updates.

### **Data Controllers and Contracting Parties**

By using any of our Service, submitting information, making a donation or a payment, engaging with WhatRocks™-labeled marketing or advertising material, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy and consent to having your data, collected, stored, transferred to and/or processed in Canada. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Service.

If you are in Europe:

* for the purposes of the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the "**GDPR**"), the data controller is WhatRocks Foundation and the data processor is WhatRocks Inc. at the address set out at ["Contact"](https://www.whatrocks.co/en/contact) below; and
    
* "information" covers all personal data processed by us, which means information that (either in isolation or in combination with other information) enables you to be identified directly or indirectly
    
* you will not need to consent to this Privacy Policy, but you acknowledge that you have read it and understood its terms.

### **Change**

WhatRocks can modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. The “**Effective Date**” legend at the top of this Privacy Policy indicates when it was last revised. Any changes will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Policy on our Service.

If you object to any changes, you may close your account. You acknowledge that your continued use of our Service after we publish or send a notice about our changes to this Privacy Policy means that the collection, storage, use and sharing of your personal data is subject to the updated Privacy Policy and that it will constitute your acceptance of any new or amended terms.

### **Third-party links**

The Service may contain links to third-party websites. Please be aware that WhatRocks cannot control and is not responsible for the information collection practices of such websites, which may differ from those of WhatRocks. We encourage you to review and understand the privacy policies of these web sites before providing any information to them.

### **Children**

Our Service is not directed to people under the age of thirteen (13) or sixteen (16) in Europe, and we do not knowingly market to, or solicit information, accept service or collect personal information from any person under the age of 13 (or 16 in Europe). If WhatRocks becomes aware that any person submitting information to the Service is under the age of 13 (or 16 in Europe), we will attempt to delete the account and any related information as soon as possible. We require that only persons 13 years of age or older (or 16 or older in Europe) use the Service. By using the Service, you hereby represent that you are at least 13 years old (or 16 in Europe).

* * *

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT**
--------------------------

To enable brands and individuals that are Members of the WhatRocks™ community to collectively redefine the marketing and advertising value exchange in a way that establishes a new social contract, the core principles of WhatRocks Foundation are that (1) brands pay a personal data dividend (“**Dividend**”, “**Rewards**”) in Rocks™ to individuals when they are exposed to, engage or interact with their WhatRocks™-labeled marketing or advertising material in respect of the commercial use of the collected personal data that remains each individual’s fully owned assets, (2) the Dividend paid by brands goes up as individuals agree to share more personal data with brands, (3) the Dividend paid to individuals is used solely for them to make donations to charities or purchase Giveback Items from Members who will in turn make donations to charities, and (4) account opening is free of charge and transactions are commission-free to keep donations untouched and allow anyone to join the WhatRocks™ community (please note that some business and technology partners of WhatRocks may charge some fees such as banking, operation and maintenance fees that are not earned directly or indirectly by WhatRocks or WhatRocks Foundation).

As WhatRocks is entrusted with the mission to implement the vision and enforce the principles of WhatRocks Foundation, we need to know a little about you and your interests to provide and run our Service and show you relevant Giveback Items, information and marketing or advertising material.

In the chart below, we have detailed the information we may collect about you, depending on your activities on the Service, and how we collect this information.

### **Information provided by Members**

**What we collect**

**How we collect it**

* * *

Your name

We require you to provide a chosen name that your personal contacts are familiar with when you create a WhatRocks™ account.

* * *

Your email address

We require you to provide a valid email address when you create a WhatRocks™ account or when you email us.

* * *

Your password

We require you to enter a secure password when you create a WhatRocks™ account.

* * *

We require you to provide your mobile number when you create a WhatRocks™ account or complete your Member profile so we may send you a security code to verify your account.

Your mobile number

* * *

You may choose to upload a profile picture when you create a WhatRocks™ account or when you complete your Member profile. Providing this information is not required to use the Service but is strongly recommended.

Your profile picture

* * *

You may choose to provide your sex when you create a WhatRocks™ account or when you complete your Member profile so we may show you relevant Giveback Items, information and charities. Providing this information is not required to use the Service but is strongly recommended.

Your sex

* * *

You may choose to provide your birthday when you create a WhatRocks™ account or when you complete your Member profile so you may receive suggestions to start a birthday fundraiser, or exclusive invitations to a local party or event, or exclusive offers and deals on relevant Giveback Items for your birthday. Providing this information is not required to use the Service but is strongly recommended.

Your birthday

* * *

When you create or edit your Member profile, we require you to select the social or environmental issues you are passionate about such as “animal rights” or “poverty alleviation”. We may use this information to personalize your user experience of our Service to show you Giveback Items, charities and fundraisers that are relevant to your interests.

Information you disclose in your Member profile about the issues you care about.

* * *

When you create or edit your Member profile, we require you to select the personal interests you are passionate about such as “concerts & festivals” or “food & drinks”. We may use this information to personalize your user experience of our Service to show you Giveback Items, charities and fundraisers that are relevant to your interests.

Information you disclose in your Member profile about your personal interests.

* * *

When you create your Member profile or when you use our Service, we require you to provide your real time geographic location to personalize your user experience of our Service to show you Giveback Items, charities and fundraisers near you. You may also earn Rocks™ when you check in from your mobile device at the specific time and place of a local event or party.

Information you disclose in your Member profile about your real time geographic location.

* * *

We may obtain certain information through your social media accounts connected to your WhatRocks™ account, if you choose to link them. Linking a social media account is not required to access and use the Service. For example, if you log in to the Service via Facebook, we ask for your permission to access certain information about your Facebook account, activities and friends. Social media sites make information available to all apps through their API, such as friend lists. The information we receive depends on what information you or the social media site decide to give us.

The Service also allows Members to access Facebook to interact with friends and to share on Facebook through Wall and friends’ News Feeds. We do this currently through a third-party service. That third-party service may store some of the information as part of their provision of services to us. If you do not use Facebook or another social networking site (SNS) to log in then that third-party does not receive any data. If you are already logged into the Service and Facebook or another SNS, when you click on "Connect with Facebook," or a similar connection on another SNS, you will be prompted to merge your profiles. If you are already logged into the Service but not logged into Facebook or another SNS that we support, when you click on "Connect with Facebook," or a similar connection on another SNS, you will be prompted to enter your SNS credentials or to "Sign Up" for the SNS. By proceeding, you are allowing the Service to access your information and you are agreeing to the Facebook or other SNS’s Terms of Use in your use of the Service. Conversely, if you are not currently registered as a Member of the WhatRocks™ community, and you click on "Sign in" using Facebook or another SNS that we support, you will first be asked to enter your Facebook or SNS credentials and then be given the option to register to the WhatRocks™ community. In this case, we may receive information from Facebook or another SNS to make it easier for you to create an account on the Service and show our relevant Giveback Items from your Facebook or SNS friends. Once you register to the WhatRocks™ community and connect with Facebook or another SNS you will be able to automatically post recent activity back to Facebook or the other SNS. Any information that we collect from your Facebook or other SNS account may depend on the privacy settings you have with that SNS, so please consult the SNS’s privacy and data practices. Further, you can edit privacy settings for the reviews that appear on Facebook, or disconnect your Service activity stream by visiting the Facebook Applications Settings page.

Your social media account ID, and information shared with us via your social media account.

* * *

You may choose to post Giveback Items or start a fundraiser publicly on the Service and share such Giveback Items or fundraiser in your social media accounts. Such information is available to the public without any expectation of privacy or confidentiality. Copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other Members have copied or stored your information even if you remove this information.

You may be offered the choice to provide other information to us. For example, we may collect information when you fill out a form, respond to surveys or provide information if we assist you by telephone, email, chat. Providing this information is not required to use the service.

If you opt to import your address book, we receive your contacts (including contact information your service provider(s) or app automatically added to your address book when you communicated with addresses or numbers not already in your list).

If you sync your contacts or calendars with our Service, we will collect your address book and calendar meeting information to keep growing your personal network by suggesting friends to go out with, and by providing information about them, e.g. personal interests, issues they care about, charities they support, location, etc.

You don’t have to post or upload any personal data; though if you don’t, you may not be able to take full advantage of the Service as it may significantly limit your ability to earn Rocks™, make donations, purchase Giveback Items and enjoy our Service generally

Any other information you voluntarily submit.

Some of the information above reveals your specific identity, or is directly tied to your specific identity, such as your name, email address and mobile number. Some of this information does not reveal your specific identity, or does not directly relate to you, such as your browser and device information or information collected through cookies. If we ever combine non-personally identifiable information with personally identifiable information, the combined information will be treated by us as personally identifying information and protected accordingly.

### **Passive Gathering of Information Electronically**

**What we collect**

**How we collect it**

* * *

Internet Protocol (IP) addresses are part of the fabric of the Internet, and are assigned to a device whenever that device connects online. When a website needs to send something to your computer (for instance search results), it needs your IP address to send it to the right device. IP Address from which your device accesses the Service may be identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever you use our Service, along with the time of your visit and the specific page(s) that you visited.

Your IP address. Your “IP Address” is a designator that is automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet Service Provider (ISP).

* * *

We use IP service Google Places API to suggest your location from real-time signals like your IP address or device location and we also use past activity on the Service to help us understand the city or country you are using our Service from and show you relevant charities to donate to as well as Giveback Items that may be of interest in your geographic area. You can change this information if it is displayed incorrectly. We do not share your information with IP service providers. Providing your geographic location is required to use the Service.

Your real-time geographic location.

* * *

When you are signed in or identified as a particular Member of the WhatRocks™ community, your activities on or connected to the Service are automatically associated with your account including the location data of your mobile device. Please note that most mobile devices allow you to manage or disable the use of location services for all applications in the settings menu.

Your specific activities on or connected to the Service including ads you have been exposed to, or engaged or interacted with, donations or payments you have made, fundraisers you have started or participated in, Items and information you have shared, and the corresponding time stamp, URLs and real time geographic location.

* * *

When you download and use any mobile applications we develop, we’ll collect your unique device ID and all your account and activity information will be tied to that unique device ID. In addition, we may track and collect app usage data, such as the date and time the app on your device accesses our servers and what information and files have been downloaded to the app. This information may be associated with your account. Giving your consent to the access, collection, storage and use of your unique mobile device ID number is required to use the Service.

Your unique mobile device ID number if you access our services via a mobile application.

* * *

The name of the web browser you use to access the Service.

Certain information is collected by most browsers or automatically through your device, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows PC or Mac), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, Internet browser type and version, and the name and version of the Service you are using. Collecting this information helps us build and deliver the best possible version of the Service to you.

* * *

As part of our efforts to connect our Members to causes that interest them, donations you make or fundraisers you start or participate in might be tagged by you, by our Members or by us as particular cause areas. For example, a charity may be tagged as “animal rights” or “poverty alleviation”. If you make a donation for a particular cause area, we may infer that you would be interested in other charities or fundraisers tagged in the same way. We may also show you charities or fundraisers that are relevant to your interest or in your general geographic area.

Information inferred about the issues you care about based on your activities on the Service.

* * *

As part of our efforts to connect our Members to Giveback Items that interest them, purchases you make might be tagged by you, by our Members or by us as particular areas of interests. For example, some Giveback Items may be tagged as “concerts & festivals” or “food & drinks”. If you make a purchase for a particular area of interest, we may infer that you would be interested in some other Giveback Items tagged in the same way. We may also show you Giveback Items that is relevant to your interest or in your general geographic area.

Information inferred about the Giveback Items you care about based on your activities on the Service.

* * *

When you interact with our Service, we try to make that experience simple and meaningful. When you use our Service, our web server sends a cookie to your computer or mobile device (as the case may be). Cookies are small text files which are issued to your computer or mobile device (as the case may be) when you visit a website or access or use a mobile application, and which store and sometimes track information about your use of the Service (as the case may be), the model or device type, operating system and version, browser type and settings, device ID or individual device identifier, advertisement ID, individual device token, and cookie-related data (e.g. cookie ID), the pages you visit, the access time and date, frequency and duration of visits, the links on which you click and other actions you take as part of your use of our Service and in advertising and email content, your activities and interactions with our advertising partners including but not limited to data about WhatRocks™-labeled marketing or advertising material you were shown, how often they were shown, when and where they were shown, and whether you took any action, such as viewing or clicking on these WhatRocks™-labeled marketing or advertising material to be financially rewarded accordingly or making a purchase. A number of cookies we use last only for the duration of your web or application session and expire when you close your browser or exit the application. Other cookies are used to remember you when you return to the Service and will last for longer.

Some of the cookies used by the Service are set by us, and some are set by third parties who are delivering services on our behalf. We, and/or our service providers may use cookies, and other similar technologies to understand Member activities. Like other services, WhatRocks will not function properly if cookies are not enabled. We may use third-party analytics services on our Service like Google Analytics provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). These service providers use cookies and other technologies to help us analyze how Members use the Service, including by noting the third-party website from which you arrive, and provide certain features to you. The information (including your IP address) collected by the technology will be disclosed to or collected directly by these service providers, who use the information to evaluate your use of the Service. This information may be used to place interest-based advertisements on the Service and on the Internet in general. This may result in you seeing advertisements for our Service as well as WhatRocks™-labeled marketing or advertising material when you visit other websites or applications. To prevent Google Analytics from using your information for analytics, you may install the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on by clicking [here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to the Service is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). These analytics services may use cookies and similar technologies to analyze how people use our Service and provide statistical reports about aggregate Member behaviour. Such services may also collect information about the use of other websites and applications.

 Most web and mobile device browsers automatically accept cookies but, if you prefer, you can change your browser’s settings to prevent that or to notify you each time a cookie is set. Please note, however, that by blocking or deleting cookies used by WhatRocks, you may not be able to take full advantage of the Service. In particular, we will not be able to inform advertisers that you should be paid a Dividend because you have seen or clicked on their WhatRocks™-labeled marketing or advertising material. Giving your consent to the use of cookies is required to use the Service. Please review our [Cookie Policy](https://www.whatrocks.co/en/cookie-policy) for detailed information on the cookies we use, and how you can manage these.

Information collected through cookies as disclosed in our linked Cookie Policy

* * *

Web beacons (also known as clear GIFs) are transparent image files. Web beacons enable WhatRocks to track usage information on our Service, such as the number of times a given web page has been viewed. Web beacons are invisible to you and (unlike cookies) are not placed on your device. We may use them in association with cookies to understand how visitors interact with the pages and content on the pages of the Service.

For instance, we may also use Web beacons to track whether you have opened an HTML email. When the email is opened, a part of the code that makes up the HTML page calls a web server to load the w

eb beacon that then generates a record showing that the email has been viewed. Web Beacons may also recognize when the email was opened, how many times it was forwarded and which URL’s (links within the email) were clicked. Giving your consent to the use of web beacons is required to use the Service.

Information collected through web beacons as disclosed in our linked Cookie Policy

* * *

In addition, we use pixel tags (also referred to as clear GIFs, web beacons, or web bugs). Pixel tags are tiny graphic images with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, that are used to track online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, pixel tags are embedded invisibly in Web pages. Pixel tags also allow us to send e-mail messages in a format users can read, and they tell us whether e-mails have been opened to ensure that we are sending only messages that are of interest to our Members. We may use this information to reduce or eliminate messages sent to a Member and we may tie the information gathered by pixel tags to information that is intended to identify our Members. Giving your consent to the use of pixel tags is required to use the Service.

Information collected through pixel tags as disclosed in our linked Cookie Policy

### **Aggregated and De-Identified Information**

From time to time, we may also ask you to provide us information that is not intended to allow us to identify you personally. This information may be aggregated and/or de-identified and used for our internal purposes or for creating reports for third-party advertisers and partners, or otherwise shared with third parties for any lawful purpose, without your permission.

We also may automatically collect usage information in connexion with our Service, such as the numbers and frequency of Members’ visits to the Service, pages visited and similar data. This data is used in the aggregate and/or is de-identified, that is, as a statistical measure, and not in a manner that is intended to identify you personally. Aggregate and de-identified information generally is collected through the use of cookies and web beacons as discussed above, but we may also aggregate or de-identify data that you provide to us. This aggregate and/or de-identified information helps WhatRocks determine general usage patterns on our Service and modify it in order to improve your user experience. This type of aggregate information may be shared with third parties at any time.

### **Information from Third Parties and other Members**

We may receive personal data (including contact information) about you when others import or sync their contacts or calendar with our Service, associate their contacts with Member profiles, or send messages using our Service (including invitations to go to an event or to participate in a fundraiser). If you or others opt-in to sync email accounts with our Service, we will also collect information that we can associate with Member profiles.

It may be necessary for us to obtain address or other information about you from third-party sources for fraud prevention or for legal compliance, to enforce our legal rights or to protect the rights of other Members of the WhatRocks™ community.

### **Information Collected from Charities**

If you are a charity and you register to the WhatRocks™ community by establishing an account with WhatRocks, we, and/or our service providers will collect the name, business number, tax ID, physical address, email address, birthday and phone number of the person who establishes a charity account and claims your charity (the "**Charity Contact**") and any other information that is required by the applicable KYC (Know Your Customer) and AML (Anti-Money Laundry) regulations. We also may collect any information to complete the profile page of your charity including the name, the description, main cause area, main geographic areas of operation, tags, any avatar and photos uploaded to the Service or any weblink to the charity’s online video presentation.

### **Information Collected from corporations**

If you are a corporation and you register to the WhatRocks™ community by establishing an account with WhatRocks, we, and/or our service providers will collect the name, business number, physical address, email address, birthday and phone number of the person who establishes a corporate account and claims your corporation (the "**Corporate Contact**") and any other information that is required by the applicable KYC (Know Your Customer) and AML (Anti-Money Laundry) regulations. We also may collect any information to complete the profile page of your corporation including the names and avatars of the advertiser and of its affiliated brands uploaded to the Service.

* * *

**HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION**
-------------------------------

We and our service providers may use your information for our legitimate business interests in providing our Service that enables brands to pay you a Dividend with their marketing or advertising spend for the commercial use of your personal data when you are exposed to or engage or interact with their WhatRocks™-labeled marketing or advertising material so you have to the money make direct or indirect donations to the charities of your choice. Our legitimate business interests are explained below, alongside examples of how your information may be used for these purposes

**Examples**

**Purpose**

* * *

* To facilitate communication between WhatRocks and you including, without limitation, responding to your questions or comments, sending emails concerning our Service including charities, fundraisers, Giveback Items, announcements, administrative information, for example, information regarding our Service and changes to our terms, conditions, and policies, or to contact you for feedback regarding us, brands or business partners.
    
* To administer your account and wallet, process Rewards, donations and payments, provide Giveback Items to you and for WhatRocks marketing and promotional activities;
    
* To provide a report to a charity or a fundraiser starter supporting a charity to which you have made a donation (even if you have marked the donation as non-public);
    
* To provide a report to a business partner or Member (including a fundraiser starter) who is helping promote a charity or a Giveback Item supporting a charity to whom you have made a donation, including your name, donation amount, time and date of donation and other related information. You contact details including your email address or mobile number will not be shared;
    
* To provide a report to our advertisers, business partners or Members that tells them who responded to a particular marketing or advertising material or Giveback Items, or to facilitate the fulfillment of an order that you have made when you purchased from a Member or business partner;
    
* To provide you with important functionality changes to the Service, new WhatRocks services and, to the extent permitted by law, special offers from WhatRocks and reputable third parties that we think you will find valuable;
    
* To ensure that our Service functions properly and is optimized for your computer or device and to store your preferences and settings.

To provide the functionality of our ecosystem. We engage in these activities to manage our contractual relationship with you and other Members.

* * *

* To show you relevant WhatRocks™-labeled marketing or advertising material in the Service and on any websites or applications so you earn Rocks™ when you are exposed to, or engage or interact with such material as a Dividend for the commercial use of your personal data,
    
* To allow you to make donations and payments, start and participate in fundraisers and to follow their progress. To allow you to participate in other activities in the Service, as well as to complete and fulfill your transactions including donations and payments.
    
* To allow you to share the Service with your contacts to grow the WhatRocks™ community. By using this feature, you guarantee that you have the right to use and provide us the names, phone number and email addresses of your contacts you submit.
    
* To allow you to send messages that you choose to send to your contacts through our Service, such as to send an invitation to a local party or event or to participate in a fundraiser. By using this feature, you guarantee that you have the right to use and provide us the names, phone number and email addresses of your contacts you submit.
    
* To facilitate the social sharing functionality that you choose to use, such as sharing content and fundraisers through the Service and other social media platforms like Facebook and Twitter.

To fulfill your specific requests through the Service. We engage in these activities to manage our contractual relationship with you and other Members

* * *

* For data analysis, for example, to improve the efficiency of our Service.
    
* For audits, to verify that our internal processes function as intended and are compliant with legal, regulatory, or contractual requirements.
    
* For fraud and security monitoring purposes, for example, to detect and prevent prohibited or illegal activities such as cyber-attacks or attempts to commit identity theft.
    
* For other legally permissible purposes and generally to ensure that we comply with applicable laws
    
* For developing new products, features and services.
    
* For customizing, analyzing, modifying, adjusting, enhancing, or improving our Service to meet our advertisers and business partners’ needs and expectations.
    
* For identifying usage trends, for example, understanding which parts of our Service are of most interest to our Members.
    
* For determining the effectiveness of fundraisers or sales of Giveback Items.
    
* For operating and expanding our business activities, for example, understanding which parts of our Service are of most interest to our Members so we can focus our efforts on meeting our Members’ interests.
    
* For legal compliance. In rare circumstances, we may have to use and disclose information we have about our Members in order to exercise or protect legal rights or defend against legal claims under applicable law.
    
* We use cookies and similar technologies detailed in our [Cookie Policy](https://www.whatrocks.co/en/privacy-policy) to measure and improve our services and develop features and functionalities on our Service. For example, if we see that people using a certain device use the Service the most, we might decide to build an app specifically for that device.
    
* We may use third-party advertising technologies that allow for the delivery of relevant Giveback Items and WhatRocks™-labeled marketing or advertising material on our Service, as well as on other websites or applications you visit. The material may be based on various factors such as the content of the page you are visiting, information you enter such as your age and gender, your searches, demographic data, user-generated content, and other information we collect from you. This material may be based on your current activity or your activity over time and across other websites and online services and may be tailored to your interests. Also, third parties whose products or services are accessible or advertised on our Service may place cookies or other tracking technologies on your computer, mobile phone, or other device to collect information about your use of the Service as discussed above. We also allow other third parties (e.g., ad networks and ad servers such as Google Analytics, DoubleClick and others) to serve tailored ads to you on our Service, as well as other websites and applications, and to access their own cookies or other tracking technologies on your computer, mobile phone, or other device you use to access the Service. We may provide our customer information (such as a hashed version of your email addresses) to service providers, who may “match” this information in de-identified form to cookies (or mobile ad identifiers) and other proprietary IDs, in order to target or “retarget” you with ads when you visit other websites and mobile applications. (You may opt out of these many of these service providers as described in the next paragraph.). We neither have access to, nor does this Privacy Policy govern, the use of cookies or other tracking technologies that may be placed on your computer, mobile phone, or other device you use to access our Service by non-affiliated, third-party ad technology, ad servers, ad networks or any other non-affiliated third parties. Those parties that use these technologies may offer you a way to opt out of ad targeting as described below. If you receive tailored advertising on your computer through a web browser, you can learn more about such tailored browser advertising and how you can generally control cookies from being put on your computer to deliver tailored advertising, by visiting the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance Consumer Ad Choices [link](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices) for EU based advertising or for US based advertising either: (i) the Network Advertising Initiative’s Consumer Opt-Out [link](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) or (ii) the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Consumer Opt-Out [link](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) to opt-out of receiving tailored advertising from companies that participate in those programs. To opt out of Google Analytics for display advertising or customize Google display network ads, you can visit the [Google Ads Settings page](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). Please note that to the extent advertising technology is integrated into our Service or other websites that you visit, you may still receive advertisements even if you opt-out. In that case, the advertising will not be tailored to your interests. Also, we do not control any of the above opt-out links or whether any particular company chooses to participate in these opt-out programs. We are not responsible for any choices you make using these mechanisms or the continued availability or accuracy of these mechanisms

To accomplish our business purposes. We engage in these activities to manage our contractual relationship with you and other Members, to comply with a legal obligation, because we have a legitimate interest, and/or with your consent.

* * *

* To customize, personalize, analyze, adjust and improve your user experience by presenting charities to donate to, and fundraisers to participate in, Giveback Items to learn about and purchase, contacts to go out wit that are tailored to you based on information we have collected from you.
    
* To associate Members’ activities, customize content, or tailor advertising to those Members across different devices and browsers (for instance, tablets, mobile devices, websites and applications).
    
* We may pseudonymize, de-identify and/or aggregate information and use such information to better understand and serve our Members or for optimization of our marketing and targeting efforts. For example, we may compile statistics like the percentage of our Members in a state or country who care about animal rights or concerts & festivals, or the age range of those Members, or to analyze the performance of particular emails.

To analyse personal information for business reporting purposes and to provide personalized services. We provide personalized services either with your consent or because we have a legitimate interest.

* * *

* Communications related to fundraisers you’ve started, other fundraisers that may be of interest, or fundraisers relevant to your location.
    
* Communications related to Giveback Items that may be of interest, or relevant to your location.
    
* Communications about specific issues or about WhatRocks.
    
* Communications about contributions to causes or about participation in a specific fundraiser, local event or party.
    
* Communications about becoming a member of the WhatRocks™ community.
    
* We may contact you by phone, SMS, or email about the WhatRocks™ community or other ways you can support charities or go to local events and parties.
    
* Invitations to WhatRocks™ events.
    
* To allow you to participate in events and similar promotions and to administer these activities. Some of these activities have additional rules, which could contain additional information about how we use and disclose information about you, so we suggest that you read these rules carefully.
    
* Most marketing communications will be sent via email, SMS, instant messaging and social media.
    
* We may remind you about particular fundraisers, local events and parties or the WhatRocks™ community, if you have not completed starting or participating in or joining.

To share marketing communications that we believe may be of interest to you. We engage in this activity with your consent, or to manage our contractual relationship with you and other Members.

For the purposes of the GDPR, we may use your information in the above ways as this is necessary: (i) to fulfill our obligations under our contract with you or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract; (ii) for our legitimate interest to maintain our relationship with you or protect you and us against fraud; or (iii) to comply with legal obligations.

* * *

**WHO MAY RECEIVE YOUR INFORMATION**
------------------------------------

WhatRocks may give, share, rent, sell or trade your pseudonymized information to or with any third parties and reward you financially in return with the payment of a Dividend under the form of fungible blockchain tokens called Rocks™ for the commercial use of your personal data when you are exposed to, or engage or interact with WhatRocks™-labeled marketing or advertising material when it is shared either by you via the Service, or by us under the following circumstances:

### **The WhatRocks™ community**

**We do not monitor, verify, or perform any background check on donors, fundraiser starters and participants, Giveback Items buyers and sellers, corporations, charities or any other Members** **of the WhatRocks™ community.**

* When you start a fundraiser via our Service, a fundraiser landing page that shows your first name, last name and general geographic location (i.e. city, state, country) is created for you. All information you post for the fundraiser (name of the fundraiser, reasons for participating in the fundraiser, videos and images, tags, fundraising goal etc.) may be displayed on the landing page for any fundraiser you start as well as on related areas of our Service, and will be visible to other Members and Visitors as we consider an online fundraiser to be a public expression of support for an issue. **If you do not wish to have your role as a fundraiser starter to be public, we recommend you do not start the fundraiser.**
    
* When you make a donation to a charity or participate in a fundraiser, your first name, last name and general geographic location (i.e. city, state, country) may be (1) displayed on the landing page for any fundraiser you start as well as on related areas of our Service and will be visible to other Members and Visitors unless you have selected the option to mark your donation or your participation in the fundraiser as non-public and not to display your name publicly, and (2) shared with the fundraiser starter or charity in the Service in addition to your donation amount, time and date of transaction, transaction identification number, and the name of the fundraiser associated with the donation. Your personal contact details such as your email address or mobile number will not be shared. **If you do not wish to have this information shared with the fundraiser starter or with the charity, please do not make any donation and do not participate in the fundraiser.**
    
* When you post Giveback Items via our Service, a Giveback Item landing page that shows your first name, last name and general geographic location (i.e. city, state, country) is created for you. All information you post for the Giveback Item (name and description of the Giveback Item, videos and images, tags, price etc.) may be displayed on the landing page for any Giveback Item you post as well as on related areas of our Service, and will be visible to other Members and Visitors as we consider that Members who purchase your Giveback Item must be able to identify who they are buying from. **If you do not wish to have your role as a Seller to be public, we recommend you do not post the Giveback Item.**
    
* When you make a purchase in the Service, your first name, last name, general geographic location (i.e. city, state, country), your payment amount, date of transaction, transaction identification number, and the name of the Giveback Item associated with the payment may be shared with the Seller. Your personal contact details such as your email address or mobile number will not be shared. **If you do not wish to have this information shared with the Seller, please do not purchase the Giveback Item.**
    
* If you choose to send invitations to go to a local event or party or to participate in a fundraiser you have started, participated in or shared with your personal contacts in the Service, you disclose your personal information to the recipient of your message.

 If you are in Europe, you may opt-out of providing your information to the fundraiser starter, the charity or the Seller for marketing purposes. However, your information will continue to be shared with the fundraiser starter, charity or Seller for auditing purposes. If you consent, or as otherwise permitted by law, we may also use the information that you provide to us to communicate with you about our current and future activities, or to notify you about any changes to our Service. If you decide that you would no longer like to receive such communications, you can opt-out from receiving such messages from WhatRocks. In order to opt-out you can click on an unsubscribe link provided at the bottom of every commercial e-mail that you receive from WhatRocks. If you opt-out, you will continue to receive communications from us relating to any donations or payments you make or other services you request or purchase.

### **Your connected social media platforms**

* You may share your activities on WhatRocks with friends on other social media sites, for example, sharing on Facebook a fundraiser you started or participated in. To do so, you must connect your WhatRocks account with your social media account. In such case, you authorize us to share information with your social media account provider, and you understand that the use of the information we share will be governed by the social media site’s privacy policy. If you do not want your information shared with other social media users or with your social media account provider, please do not connect your social media account with your WhatRocks account and do not use the social sharing features on the Service.
    
* You may voluntarily share information on message boards, chats, profile pages, blogs, and other services to which you are able to post information and materials (including the WhatRocks pages on Facebook and other social media platforms). Please note that any information you post or disclose through these services will become public information, and may be available to other Members, social media platform users and to the general public. We urge you to be very careful when deciding to disclose any information about yourself via the social sharing features of our Service.

### **Our business entities and service providers**

We may retain other companies and individuals to perform certain functions on our behalf. Examples include, but are not limited to, companies and individuals who: (i) administer the WhatRocks accounts and wallets; (ii) process donations and payments; (iii) conduct surveys or promotional activities; (iv) deliver products or services; or (v) provide customer support, web hosting, internet service, and data analysis. Such third parties may be provided with access to your information needed to perform their functions but may not use such information for any other purpose.

We may share your information with third parties for the following purposes:

* Our affiliates, which are entities under common ownership or control of WhatRocks, to provide our Service globally and for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.
    
* WhatRocks Foundation on behalf and in the name of which WhatRocks develops and manages the WhatRocks™ community.
    
* Our suppliers, subcontractors and business partners (“**Service Providers**”): We may share information about you with our Service Providers who process information to provide services to us or on our behalf. We have contracts with our Service Providers that prohibit them from sharing the information about you that they collect or receive with anyone else or from using such information for other purposes. 

In the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, dissolution or sale or transfer of substantially all of the assets (a “**Liquidation Event**”) of WhatRocks or the Service, or the diligence related to a Liquidation Event, your information may be sold, assigned or transferred to the party acquiring all or substantially all of the equity and/or assets of WhatRocks or the Service in order to permit the party to continue the operation of WhatRocks and/or the Service or any successor version of the Service. By using the Service, you consent to the sale and transfer of your information as described in this paragraph. Our successors and assigns may collect and use your information for substantially similar purposes as described in this Privacy Policy.

At any time and for any reason without any disadvantage or prejudice, WhatRocks Foundation may decide to entrust an entity other than WhatRocks or its affiliates with the mission to implement its vision and enforce its principles of WhatRocks Foundation and to operate on its behalf and in its name to support the development and the management of the WhatRocks™ community of WhatRocks Foundation, the delivery of WhatRocks™-labeled marketing or advertising material to Members of the WhatRocks™ community as well as the processing of transactions such as financial rewards, donations and payments, your information may be assigned or transferred to this new entity to enable it to continue the operation of the Service or any successor version of the Service. By using the Service, you consent to the transfer of your information as described in this paragraph. Our successors and assigns may collect and use your information for substantially similar purposes as described in this Privacy Policy. In such an event, we shall delete all your information and we shall keep no records of your personal data.

### **Legal & administrative obligations**

We may disclose any information we deem necessary, in our sole discretion and without your prior permission, to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request. We may also exchange information with other companies and organizations for credit fraud protection, risk reduction and related activities or to protect the rights, property of safety and of WhatRocks, its agents, employees or affiliates or others. WhatRocks reserves the right to use and to disclose to third parties the information of a user who we believe is in violation of our Privacy Policy or other terms as posted on the Service, even without a subpoena, warrant, court order or other governmental request, to the extent we deem necessary to protect the safety, security and rights of WhatRocks and of third parties.

We may use and disclose your personal information as necessary or appropriate, especially when we have a legal obligation or legitimate interest to do so:

* Fraud prevention: We may use and disclose the information we collect from and about our users as we believe necessary to investigate, prevent, or respond to suspected illegal or fraudulent activity or to protect the safety, privacy, rights, or property of us, our users, or others.
    
* Law enforcement purposes: If requested or required by government authorities such as law enforcement authorities, courts, regulators, or otherwise to comply with the law (which may include laws outside your country of residence), we may have to disclose information we have about our users. We also may use and disclose information collected about you in order to exercise or protect legal rights or defend against legal claims.
    
* Sale or merger of our company: We may use, disclose, or transfer your personal information to a third party if we or any of our company affiliates are involved in a corporate restructuring (e.g., a sale, merger, or other transfer of assets, including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).

* * *

**YOUR PRIVACY CHOICES**
------------------------

You can edit your privacy settings and the emails you receive from WhatRocks at any time through our “Settings” page. If you want, you can ask us for the information we have about your account and even ask us to delete it all.

### **Account & email settings**

If you no longer want to receive marketing-related emails from WhatRocks going forward, you may opt out of receiving these by following the instructions contained in any such email. We will comply with your request(s) as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that if you opt out of receiving marketing-related emails from us, we may still send you important administrative messages (such as updates about your account or service changes), from which you cannot opt out.

### **Accessing or deleting your information**

If you would like to request to review, correct, update, suppress, or delete personal information that has been previously provided to us by you, you may log in to your account, click on “Settings” and update your profile information.

If you are in Europe, you have the right if applicable to request:

* a copy of the information we are processing about you,
    
* the rectification of incomplete or inaccurate information,
    
* the deletion of information that we process about you, except we are not obliged to do so if we need to retain such data in order to comply with a legal obligation or to establish, exercise or defend legal claims.
    
* the restriction of our processing of your information where you believe such data to be inaccurate; our processing is unlawful; or that we no longer need to process such data for a particular purpose unless we are not able to delete the data due to a legal or other obligation or because you do not wish for us to delete it.
    
* the portability of you information we hold about you to obtain information it in a structured, electronic format, and to transmit such data to another data controller, where this is (a) information which you have provided to us, and (b) if we are processing that data on the basis of your consent or to perform a contract with you.
    
* the objection to the processing of your information on grounds relating to your particular situation where the legal basis for such processing is our legitimate interest. We will abide by your request unless we have compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, or if we need to continue to process the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of a legal claim.
    
* the withdrawal of your consent to our processing of your information, at any time, free of charge. This includes where you wish to opt out from marketing messages.

### **SOCIAL MEDIA**

You can edit or remove the permissions you have granted to WhatRocks to use information from your social media accounts by using your application privacy settings on your social media account If you have signed in on WhatRocks through Facebook connect, you are likely to have been cookied by Facebook. You can modify or change those cookies through the settings on your Facebook account. For more details on cookies, please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.whatrocks.co/en/cookie-policy).

### **Third-party analytics companies & Cookies**

We have provided details on the cookies we use and instructions for how you can opt out of these in our [Cookie Policy](https://www.whatrocks.co/en/cookie-policy).

* * *

**DATA RETENTION**
------------------

We will retain your Personal Information for as long as needed or permitted in light of the purposes for which it was obtained. The criteria used to determine our retention periods include the length of time we have an ongoing relationship with you and provide our Service to you, our legal obligations or whether retention is advisable in light of our legal position (such as in regard to applicable statutes of limitations, litigation or regulatory investigations).

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to your request. There may also be residual information that will remain within our databases and other records, but such residual information will no longer be tied to your identity. For example, if you started a fundraiser or posted a Giveback Item, we will have records that other Members participated in your fundraiser. If you subsequently ask us to delete your information from our Service and databases, information related to those other Members’ participations cannot be removed and will remain in our records.

* * *

**CROSS-BORDER TRANSFERS**
--------------------------

WhatRocks is an organization with a global presence, so your information may be transferred across borders when you use the Service. Your personal information may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers, and by using the Service you consent to the transfer of your personal information to countries outside of your country of residence, including Canada, which may have different data protection rules from those of your country. In certain circumstances, courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies, or security authorities in those other countries may be entitled to access your personal information. 

Some of the non-European Economic Area (“EEA”) countries are recognized by the European Commission as providing an adequate level of data protection according to EEA standards, and the full list of these countries is available [here](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en). For transfers from the EEA to countries not considered adequate by the European Commission, we put in place adequate measures, such as standard contractual clauses adopted by the European Commission to protect your personal information.

* * *

**THIRD PARTY SERVICES**
------------------------

We’re not responsible for the privacy practices of third parties linked to our Service.

This Privacy Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information, or other practices of any third parties, including any third party operating any site or service to which our Service links. Our inclusion of a link on our Service does not imply our endorsement of the linked site or service.

* * *

**DATA SECURITY**
-----------------

We take a lot of measures to protect your personal information. If you suspect someone else is using your account, let us know by [contacting us.](https://www.whatrocks.co/en/contact) We seek to use reasonable organizational, technical, and administrative measures to protect your personal information within our organization from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration and/or destruction. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify our Data Protection Team at dpt@whatrocks.co.

We maintain a variety of safeguards designed to protect your information from unauthorized access, loss, misuse, alteration and disclosure. For example, we use industry accepted tools and techniques to protect against unauthorized access to our systems. We implement both physical and technological protocols to limit access to your information. These safeguards and tools vary based on the sensitivity of the information that we maintain about you.

You should be aware, however, that WhatRocks has no control over the security of other websites on the Internet that you might visit even when a link may appear to those websites from our Service. If you share your device or use a device that is accessed by the general public, remember to sign off and close your browser window when you have finished your session. This will help to ensure that others cannot access your information.

We want you to feel confident using the Service. However, no system can be completely secure. Therefore, although we take measures to secure your information, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your information, searches or other communications always will remain secure. In the event of a breach of the confidentiality or security of your information, we will notify you if reasonably possible and as legally required so that you can take appropriate protective steps. We may notify you under such circumstances using the email address(es) we have on record for you. You should also take care with who you handle and disclose your information.

* * *

**USERS FROM OUTSIDE CANADA**
-----------------------------

The Service is hosted in Canada and are governed by Canadian law. If you are using the Service from outside Canada, please be aware that your information may be collected, transferred to, stored and processed in Canada where our servers are located and our central database is operated. The data protection and other laws of Canada and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country. By using the Service, you consent to your information being transferred to our facilities and to the facilities of those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy.

Proud member of

[Terms of Use](https://www.whatrocks.co/en/terms-of-use) - [Community Guidelines](https://www.whatrocks.co/en/community-guidelines) - [Privacy policy](https://www.whatrocks.co/en/privacy-policy) - [Cookie policy](https://www.whatrocks.co/en/cookie-policy) - [Download on Android](https://www.whatrocks.co/en/whatrocks-for-android-google-play-store)
